{
  "sourceFile": "2018-2019-International-Geography-Bee-Regional-Quiz-Tournament-Round-2.txt",
  "count": 10,
  "items": [
    {
      "qno": 1,
      "question": "The Psychro Cave is a mythical birthplace on this island also home to Lake Kournas and Mount Ida. Chania and Heraklion are cities on this island separated from the mainland by the Kythira Strait. British archaeologist Arthur Evans excavated an ancient palace containing a fresco of a man leaping over a bull on this island south of the Peloponnesus. The Minoan palace of Knossos was built on, for the point, what largest Greek island?",
      "answer": "Crete"
    },
    {
      "qno": 2,
      "question": "In this city, the restaurant Brennan’s created a dish of bananas served in butter and brown sugar now known as Bananas Foster. Beignets [ben-YAYZ], fried dough pastries covered with sugar, were popularized by this city’s Cafe du Monde. Popular dishes in this city include muffuletta sandwiches, po’ boys, and gumbo. This city’s French Quarter contains Bourbon Street. For the point, name this most populous city in Louisiana.",
      "answer": "New Orleans"
    },
    {
      "qno": 3,
      "question": "This country’s Chuquicamata [Chuh-Quick-a-mah-tuh] is the world’s largest open-pit copper mine by volume. This country controls the Juan Fernandez Islands, which includes Robinson Crusoe Island, while its Atacama Desert sparked the War of the Pacific. Easter Island is controlled by, for the point, what country with its capital at Santiago?",
      "answer": "Republic of Chile"
    },
    {
      "qno": 4,
      "question": "This city’s namesake creek was once a major pearling center, but was dredged in the 1960s to develop its port infrastructure. One line of this city’s driverless Metro runs alongside Sheikh Zayed Road. The Palm Jumeirah and The World are artificial island groups located in the Persian Gulf in this city. For the point, the Burj Khalifa is in what most populous city of the United Arab Emirates?",
      "answer": "Dubai"
    },
    {
      "qno": 5,
      "question": "A 36-course meal known as wazwan is native to this region. This region’s city of Muzaffarabad lies at the junction of the Neelum and Jhelum [Jay-lum] Rivers. Srinagar [Shree-nuh-gur] is the capital of an Indian state in this region west of the disputed territory of Aksai Chin. The Siachen Glacier is located near the Line of Control in, for the point, what region claimed by both Pakistan and India?",
      "answer": "Kashmir"
    },
    {
      "qno": 6,
      "question": "According to local legend, the devil once helped construct a bridge in this mountain range’s Schöllenen Gorge. Lake Lucerne is in this mountain range crossed by the Brenner Pass and St. Bernard Pass. Famous skiing destinations in this mountain range include Mont Blanc and the Matterhorn. For the point, name this mountain range that covers much of Austria and Switzerland.",
      "answer": "The Alps"
    },
    {
      "qno": 7,
      "question": "This country and Pakistan are building a namesake “Economic Corridor” that includes the reconstruction of the Karakoram Highway. This country is building railroads in East Africa and Southeast Asia as part of its One Belt, One Road initiative. Shenzhen [SHEN-JEN] and Xiamen [SHEAH-MEN] were some of the first Special Economic Zones in this country. For the point, the Yuan [Yu-an] is the currency of what country with its capital at Beijing?",
      "answer": "People’s Republic of China"
    },
    {
      "qno": 8,
      "question": "This region’s Kluane [kloo AH nee] National Park is home to the second-highest peak in North America, while its city of Dawson was founded during a gold rush on the Klondike River. This territory’s eastern border is formed by the Mackenzie River, while its share of the St. Elias Mountains includes Mount Logan. For the point, name this westernmost Canadian territory with its capital at Whitehorse.",
      "answer": "Yukon Territory"
    },
    {
      "qno": 9,
      "question": "The Aubrey Holes are 56 chalk pits discovered near this location. Historians believe sarsens were transported up the River Avon north of Salisbury to build this landmark, a former site for Druidic religious ceremonies. This site may have been designed to align with the sun on the summer solstice. For the point, name this prehistoric site in England, a large circle of stacked megaliths.",
      "answer": "Stonehenge"
    },
    {
      "qno": 10,
      "question": "One island in this country is the namesake of dracaena cinnabari, a type of dragon tree. The Wadi Hadhramaut [Had-ruh-maut] is in the east of this country that has no permanent rivers. Socotra is an island belonging to this country that contains the southwest portion of the Empty Quarter. The Bab-el-Mandeb lies between Djibouti and, for the point, what country with cities Aden and Sanaa?",
      "answer": "Republic of Yemen"
    }
  ]
}